Daniel McManus

N89W6903 Evergreen Ct. #204 Cedarburg, WI 53012

E: danmcmanus11@outlook.com P: (414) 940-4150

https://github.com/danmcmanus

Professional Summary

I am a software development professional with a diverse professional background including business, finance, sales and technical training which has given me a unique hybrid of skills. I have a demonstrated proficiency in C#, SQL, and a variety of Javascript frameworks. I have nearly 3 years of previous experience on Enterprise level, client facing web and mobile applications. Business leadership experience includes managing time-sensitive materials, streamlining processes, increasing revenue, and managing IT solutions. I practice agile methodologies on a daily basis.

EDUCATION

devCodeCamp, Milwaukee, WI

October 2015 - April 2016

devCodeCamp is an immersive 600 hour software development boot camp in C# .NET development with an introduction to Python, ASP.NET, and JavaScript. It involves paired programming, intense lectures, mentorship, and a wide variety of challenging individual and group projects.

University of Wisconsin - Milwaukee

2001 - 2003

Port Washington High School

1998 - 2001

TECHNICAL AND ANALYTICAL SKILLS

- · C#/.NET
- · JavaScript, HTML, CSS, LESS, SASS
- · AngularJS, Angular 7+
- · Grunt, Gulp, Webpack
- · NodeJS
- · Bootstrap, Material Design
- · SQL, MSSQL, SSMS
- · GIT
- · Scrum
- · Jira
- · Entity Framework, Dapper
- · Unit Testing, Integration Testing, TDD
- Jenkins
- Serverless
- · AWS Cloud Computing (Lambda, ApiGateway, DynamoDb)
- Project Coordination

- · Business Development
- · Sales
- · Insurance (Life/Health/LTC/DI)

APPLICATION DEVELOPMENT EXPERIENCE

I have extensive Enterprise level application development experience, having worked in all aspects of the Milwaukee Tool One-Key Inventory Management Solution, an ASP.NET MVC/Web API application. Since the time I joined Milwaukee Tool, we have been transitioning this application from a monolithic architecture to a microservice/serverless oriented architecture. This has given me extensive experience and training with AWS cloud computing, with specific expertise in AWS Lambda, DynamoDB, S3, SNS and SQS. I also work extensively within the Serverless framework. I am in charge of all localization within the web application, as well as the implementation of our GDPR compliance

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Milwaukee Tool, Brookfield, WI

Software Developer, OneKey Team

August 2016 - present

(The gap in employment was while attending devCodeCamp)

Central Financial Services, Milwaukee, WI

<u>Licensed Insurance Agent</u>

March 2011 – October 2015

Product lines included:

- · Life
- · Health
- · Long-Term Care
- · Disability/Critical Care
- · Annuities

Key responsibilities included:

- · Policy analysis recommendations
- Managing client communications
- · Delivering prompt, professional customer service
- · Financial Analysis for personal and business clients

The Pasta Shoppe, Port Washington, WI

August 1998 - March 2011

General Manager/Restaurant Manager

References available upon request.